Esteban Ordenes



emordenes2014@gmail.com



954.470.1796



linkedin.com/in/estebanordenes



https://github.com/emordenes/DataAnalvstPortfolio



https://eportfolio.greatlearning.in/esteban-ordenes

Summary

Certified in Data Science and Business Analytics, and experienced Software Engineer, with highly analytical, process-oriented skills. Has extensive knowledge in development of SQL queries, data curation, wrangling, manipulation and visualization. Ability to provide insights, analytics and business intelligence used to advance opportunity identification, process reengineering.

Passion for problem-solving and leveraging data. Competent to work in any organization that aims to create impact and build meaningful relationships with its consumers. Looking forward to expanding career in Data Science, has 15+ years experience as a Software Engineer. Major strengths are dedication to provide sound and stable business insights and solutions.

Skills

T-SQL • Integration • Agile Methodologies • Software Development • Requirements Analysis • Python (Programming Language) • Data Science • Tableau • Statistical Modeling • Data Visualization • Supervised Learning and Classification • Ensemble Techniques • Model Tuning • Unsupervised Learning • SSIS • Pentaho Data Integration(spoon/kettle) • MS .Net • C# • MVC API •

Experience



Data Analyst/Software Engineer

LexisNexis Risk Solutions

Aug 2017 - Present (4 years 2 months +)

- Produce Exploratory Data Analysis and Modeling Techniques for technical teams to analyze system performance data in order to support Data Content Acquisition decisions to improve data collection. This led to improving data collection rates from 70% to 85%.
- · Responsible for data content acquisition, creating and maintaining spiders and crawlers for 50000+ recurring web resources. Gathering, sanitizing, organizing and integrating data for production processing. Develop and support business solutions and provide insights for business users and stakeholders. MSSQL, Python, Tableau, ETL(PDI).

Software Engineer

NCCI

Apr 2016 - Aug 2017 (1 year 5 months)

 Design and develop applications in support of customer service and subscription based services. MSSQL

Senior Software Engineer - Contractor

Wealth Management Systems, Inc (WMSI) - A DST Company

Jun 2014 - Aug 2015 (1 year 3 months)

- Technical Lead Developer of Product Development Team on a specific retirement planning product. WMSI develops technology solutions which include IRA rollover services in the financial services industry including financial education, planning tools and advisor solutions.
- Import data from multiple sources and ETL processing. This data would feed into WMSI's products, which later could be used for customer account credentialing.MSSQL

Software Developer III

MTN. a Global Eagle Brand

Nov 2010 - Feb 2014 (3 years 4 months)

- Designs, develops and implements a variety of software applications. These include web pages and services, as well as console applications and windows services.
- Participated in the support and development of a credit card capture and authorization platform that integrated telephony services into the credit card billing system.
- ETL of Long Distance system to the newly implemented Porta-One platform. This migration required understanding of how the Porta-One billing system works and integrated the generated bills into Dynamics GP (Great Plains) billing module and Dynamics CRM platform. MSSQL, MySQL, ETL.

Sr. Software Engineer

US Installation Group

Aug 2008 - Oct 2010 (2 years 3 months)

- Contributor of the Software Development Team for a service provider for The Home Depot.Designed, Documented, developed and implemented a variety of software applications. These include web pages and windows services, as well as console applications.
- Participated in the design and development of many projects which include the Next Generation Project in which the company is converting from its classic ASP site to

Microsoft .NET technologies. This conversion, as well as UI changes, includes redesigning and enhancing the back-end processes and implementing new business requirements.

 Directly involved in various applications such as the Installer Compliance module, Bale Recycling System, Voice-Of-Customer and Inventory reports, Account Payables and the automation of workflow for The Home Depot purchase orders.

Sr. Software Engineer

Kaplan

Jul 2006 - Aug 2008 (2 years 2 months)

- Worked with the Post-Enrollment Academics Development Team. Participated in the design and development of many projects that add-on to the Student Portal web site where its main functionality is for students to log-in and attend classes as well as manage all information regarding the student and faculty, including Student Aid and Ledger Card, Instructor Concerns, Faculty Information Management, Student Assessment Portfolio Management.
- Main player in the Faculty Information Management System (Phase I) that would manage instructor's academia and courses integrating external systems such as PeopleSoft and Kenexa Brassring. The newly implemented system significantly decreased the administration effort of keeping track of faculty's academic information.

Education



The University of Texas at Austin

Postgraduate Degree, Data Science and Business Analytics (2021)



Universidad Tecnológica Metropolitana

Bachelor Science, Information Technology (Chile, 1996 - 2000)



DUOC UC (Chile, 1992 - 1995)

Associates Degree, IT Systems Analysis

Languages

Spanish: Native/Bilingual